

ANUJ SHARMA

Agriculturist • Plant Pathologist • Epidemiologist • Data Scientist

2+1 352-213-7190

anujs.com.np

rknx@outlook.com

in sharmaan

♀ Gainesville, FL

MOTIVATION

I am currently a PhD candidate in Plant Pathology and have passion for research. I am a fast learner and am enthusiastic to learn new and cutting-edge science. I am known to be punctual and hardworking. I am creative, self-motivated and capable of taking leadership role to design and carry out research experiments. I take pride in my ability to work collaboratively and communicate efficiently with a team. I am credited for having an eye for the detail, ability to work under pressure, and advanced computer expertise.

SKILLS

DNA cloning Genomic analysis RNA-seq analysis Gene mapping

Experiment design

Predictive modeling I

Microsoft office Shell scripting

Genotyping

R language

Python language

Scientific writing Web design

LANGUAGES

English Nepali Spanish

WORK EXPERIENCE

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

2017 - 2021

University of Florida, Department of Plant Pathology

Gainesville, FL, USA

- Developed statistical models for bacterial dispersal in field and nursery to elucidate the role of effectors in dispersal.
- Performed transcriptomic analysis of citrus to investigate the changes in response to citrus canker.
- Designed and executed experiments to determine the mutation rate of Xanthomonas TAL effectors.
- Characterized novel bacterial spot resistance and mapped the resistance genes in pepper.
- Wrote and published scientific research and review papers.
- Peer reviewed research manuscript for multiple journals.

TEACHING ASSISTANT

2019 - 2020

University of Florida, Department of Plant Pathology

Gainesville, FL, USA

- Lab preparation, lab introduction, supervision, and grading.
- ▶ Designed *TA's choice* labs, including lectures and assessments.
- Guest lectures in bacterial and fungal plant pathogen courses.

RESEARCH INTERN

2016 - 2017

Nepal Agriculture Research Council

Pokhara, Nepal

- Performed coordinated varietal trials of several vegetables.
- Undertook coffee rust biocontrol trial for organic production.
- Generated and evaluated hybrid tomato for blight tolerance.
- Mentored Junior Technical Assistants and extension agents.

EDUCATION

PHD IN PLANT PATHOLOGY

2021 (EXPECTED)

University of Florida, Department of Plant Pathology

BS IN AGRICULTURE

2016

Tribhuvan University, Institute of Agriculture and Animal Science

PUBLICATIONS

Please visit https://anujs.com.np/.

REFERENCES

To be provided upon request.

